[
    {
        "question": " अनुराग",
        "options": [
            "वीतराग",
            "अराग",
            "वैराग्य",
            "विराग"
        ],
        "answer": "विराग"
    },
    {
        "question": "कृतज्ञ",
        "options": [
            "शिष्ट",
            "अपकर्ष",
            "कृतघ्न",
            "अनृत"
        ],
        "answer": "कृतघ्न"
    },
    {
        "question": "अग्रज",
        "options": [
            "लघु",
            "अनुज",
            "कनिष्ठ",
            "छोटा"
        ],
        "answer": "अनुज"
    },
    {
        "question": "अमर",
        "options": [
            "मानव",
            "मर्त्य",
            "असुर",
            "मरणशील"
        ],
        "answer": "मर्त्य"
    },
    {
        "question": "अमावस्या",
        "options": [
            "पूनम",
            "पूनो",
            "पूर्णिमा",
            "पूर्णमासी"
        ],
        "answer": "पूर्णिमा"
    },
    {
        "question": " एक",
        "options": [
            "बिस्तर",
            "अनेक",
            "बहुत से",
            "भूरि"
        ],
        "answer": "अनेक"
    },
    {
        "question": "कनिष्ठ",
        "options": [
            "श्रेष्ठ",
            "प्रधान",
            "उत्तम",
            "वरिष्ठ"
        ],
        "answer": "वरिष्ठ"
    },
    {
        "question": " पंडित",
        "options": [
            "अनाङी",
            "मूर्ख",
            "अज्ञानी",
            "मूढ"
        ],
        "answer": "मूर्ख"
    },
    {
        "question": "न्यून",
        "options": [
            "कम",
            "बहुत",
            "ज्यादा",
            "अधिक"
        ],
        "answer": "अधिक"
    },
    {
        "question": "नख",
        "options": [
            "चोटी",
            "केशपाश",
            "शिख",
            "चूड़ा"
        ],
        "answer": "शिख"
    },
    {
        "question": "निर्दयी",
        "options": [
            "दयालु",
            "कृपालु",
            "दयावान",
            "झगड़ालु"
        ],
        "answer": "दयालु"
    },
    {
        "question": " लाभ",
        "options": [
            "घाटा",
            "हानि",
            "नुकसान",
            "अलाभ"
        ],
        "answer": "हानि"
    },
    {
        "question": "मानव",
        "options": [
            "राक्षस",
            "दनुज",
            "निशाचर",
            "दानव"
        ],
        "answer": "दानव"
    },
    {
        "question": " दक्षिण",
        "options": [
            "उत्तर",
            "वाम",
            "दोनों",
            "इनमें से कोई नहीं"
        ],
        "answer": "दोनों"
    },
    {
        "question": "मूक",
        "options": [
            "नवीन",
            "पंगु",
            "वधिर",
            "वाचाल"
        ],
        "answer": "वाचाल"
    },
    {
        "question": " सूक्ष्म",
        "options": [
            "अदृश्य",
            "स्थूल",
            "निश्चित",
            "दृष्टव्य"
        ],
        "answer": "स्थूल"
    },
    {
        "question": " अति",
        "options": [
            "नगण्य",
            "कम",
            "न्यून",
            "अल्प"
        ],
        "answer": "अल्प"
    },
    {
        "question": " श्रीगणेश",
        "options": [
            "श्रीकृष्ण",
            "पार्वती",
            "विनाग",
            "इतिश्री"
        ],
        "answer": "इतिश्री"
    },
    {
        "question": " उर्वर",
        "options": [
            "ऊसर",
            "उत्कृष्ट",
            "प्रवर",
            "निकृष्ट"
        ],
        "answer": "ऊसर"
    },
    {
        "question": "महान",
        "options": [
            "अनुचित",
            "नगण्य",
            "अल्प",
            "क्षुद्र"
        ],
        "answer": "क्षुद्र"
    },
    {
        "question": "राजा",
        "options": [
            "रानी",
            "रंक",
            "प्रजा",
            "ये सभी"
        ],
        "answer": "ये सभी"
    },
    {
        "question": "उपमान",
        "options": [
            "उपमा",
            "उपमेय",
            "व्यतिरेक",
            "प्रतीप"
        ],
        "answer": "उपमेय"
    },
    {
        "question": "संन्यासी",
        "options": [
            "योगी",
            "भोगी",
            "राजा",
            "गृहस्थ"
        ],
        "answer": "गृहस्थ"
    },
    {
        "question": "अल्पज्ञ",
        "options": [
            "बहुज्ञ",
            "विज्ञ",
            "अज्ञ",
            "सर्वज्ञ"
        ],
        "answer": "बहुज्ञ"
    },
    {
        "question": " गृहीत",
        "options": [
            "लिप्त",
            "सुप्त",
            "व्यक्त",
            "त्यक्त"
        ],
        "answer": "त्यक्त"
    }
]